export const BUSINESSMANAGEMENTA2018 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. A business organization whose source of capital is from government subvention or grants is a",
A: "co-operative society.",
B: "public corporation.",
C: "public limited liability company.",
D: "small-scale enterprise.",
answer: "B. public corporation",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. State-owned enterprises must at least break-even. This means",
A: "their prices must be affordable.",
B: "N their profit must exceed their operational cost.",
C: "they must generate revenue to just cover cost.",
D: "they must maximize profit.",
answer: "B. their profit must exceed their operational cost",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. A person who wants information about the history and viability of a company for the purpose of buying shares must look for the",
A: "articles of association.",
B: "proposal.",
C: "prospectus.",
D: "regulation of a company.",
answer: "C. prospectus.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. An effective way to enhance co-ordination in an organization is through",
A: "adequate planning.",
B: "committee meetings.",
C: "regular delegation.",
D: "staff motivation.",
answer: "A. adequate panning.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. The exchange of services between two countries is",
A: "balance of trade.",
B: "invisible trade.",
C: "terms of trade.",
D: "visible trade.",
answer: "B. invisible trade",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. The last element in the channel of distribution is the",
A: "consumer.",
B: "distributor.",
C: "importer.",
D: "wholesaler.",
answer: "A. consumer.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. Governments can protect infant industries from foreign competition by",
A: "giving them loans.",
B: "increasing excise duties.",
C: "increasing tariffs.",
D: "reducing the exchange rates.",
answer: "C. increasing tariffs.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. An investor who buys shares at lower prices hoping to sell at a higher price is",
A: "an agent.",
B: "a bear.",
C: "a bull.",
D: "a jobber.",
answer: "C. a bull.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. Which of the following taxes is a component of customs duty?",
A: "Income tax",
B: "Excise duty",
C: "Export duty",
D: "Sales tax",
answer: "C. Export duty",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. An exporter who deals in tangible goods is engaged in",
A: "counter trade.",
B: "entrepot trade.",
C: "invisible trade.",
D: "visible trade.",
answer: "D. visible trade.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. The stage of integration which involves member nations having the same monetary and fiscal policies is",
A: "common market.",
B: "customs union.",
C: "economic union.",
D: "free trade area.",
answer: "C. economic union",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. Which of the following insurance policies must be taken by a shipper to cover transportation cost?",
A: "Endowment insurance",
B: "Freight insurance",
C: "Goods-in-transit insurance",
D: "Third party insurance",
answer: "B. Freight insurance",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. A narrow span of control means",
A: "few subordinates report to top management.",
B: "the employee should take instructions from only one manager.",
C: "the manager supervises only few subordinates.",
D: "the organization’s decisions are taken by selected managers.",
answer: "A. few subordinates report to top management",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. An agent who sells in his own name is a",
A: "broker.",
B: "del credere agent.",
C: "factor agent.",
D: "jobber.",
answer: "D. jobber.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. Any company that wants to produce goods to satisfy the lifestyle and culture of customers must examine the",
A: "economic environment.",
B: "legal environment.",
C: "social environment.",
D: "technical environment.",
answer: "B. legal environment",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. Communication is effective when",
A: "the information is conveyed and received.",
B: "the information passes through the right channel.",
C: "there is appropriate feedback.",
D: "the message is backed by law.",
answer: "C. there is appropriate feedback",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. According to Maslow’s hierarchy of needs, a recently employed graduate would be motivated by",
A: "physiological needs.",
B: "safety needs.",
C: "social needs.",
D: "esteem needs.",
answer: "A. physiological needs",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. To prevent difficulties in decoding instructions by employees, managers must avoid the use of",
A: "microphone.",
B: "intercom.",
C: "jargons.",
D: "memorandum.",
answer: "C. jargons.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. The responses given by customers to a marketing researcher are known as",
A: "data.",
B: "information.",
C: "record.",
D: "views.",
answer: "A. data.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. When a party performs part of work and abandons the rest, he can be paid by",
A: "an injunction.",
B: "claim for damages.",
C: "ex gratia.",
D: "quantum meruit.",
answer: "D. quantum meruit.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. When auditors are engaged to assess the operations of an organization, management is performing the function of",
A: "planning.",
B: "organizing.",
C: "directing.",
D: "controlling.",
answer: "D. controlling.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. Failure to fulfil one of the terms of a contract is a",
A: "breach of condition.",
B: "breach of warranty.",
C: "misrepresentation.",
D: "mistake.",
answer: "A. breach of condition.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. An advertisement to promote a company’s product is",
A: "external communication.",
B: "formal communication.",
C: "informal communication.",
D: "internal communication.",
answer: "A. external communication",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. Which pricing technique is used when a producer wants to sell more at low prices?",
A: "cost-plus pricing",
B: "Flexible pricing",
C: "Penetration pricing",
D: "Skimming pricing",
answer: "C. Penetration pricing",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. Which of the following business practices ensures continuous production levels and avoids wastage in an organization?",
A: "Engaging only in cash sales",
B: "Good inventory control",
C: "Keeping of proper accounts",
D: "Regular balance sheet analysis",
answer: "B. Good inventory control.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. One characteristic of an entrepreneur is that he",
A: "believes in dependency on others for business success.",
B: "has a strong desire to take charge and control a business.",
C: "ignores businesses that start with small capital.",
D: "strives to be a chief executive officer of a company.",
answer: "B. has a strong desire to take charge and control a business.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. The process of establishing a challenging job which motivates and brings satisfaction to employees is",
A: "job analysis.",
B: "job enlargement.",
C: "job enrichment.",
D: "job evaluation.",
answer: "C. job enrichment",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. A group of people whose activities affect the operations of a business are its",
A: "concerned citizens.",
B: "concerned observers.",
C: "debenture holders.",
D: "stakeholders.",
answer: "D. stakeholders.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. Strategic decisions are made by",
A: "heads of department.",
B: "middle level management.",
C: "office supervisors.",
D: "top level management.",
answer: "D. top level management.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. The central processing unit of a computer contains the",
A: "hardware, control units and memory.",
B: "memory, arithmetic logical and control unit.",
C: "memory, control unit and display unit.",
D: "software, keyboard and memory.",
answer: "B. memory, arithmetic logical and control unit.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. One method of training that allows the trainee to be part of the production process is",
A: "apprenticeship.",
B: ". coaching.",
C: "role playing.",
D: "vestibule training.",
answer: "A. apprenticeship.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. Capacity as it relates to law of contract means that the parties",
A: "can engage in illegal business.",
B: "must have paid their taxes up to date.",
C: "must have funds to execute the contract.",
D: "must be more than 18 years old.",
answer: "D. must he more than 18 years old",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. Welfare services that can be offered by organizations include provision of",
A: "hoist and lifts.",
B: "protective clothing.",
C: "recreational facilities.",
D: "training facilities.",
answer: "C. recreational facilities.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. Mensah paid GH¢800 to Robert Limited a Korean firm to send contraband goods to Canada, such a contract is",
A: "enforceable.",
B: "fraudulent.",
C: "void.",
D: "voidable.",
answer: "C. void.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. Which of the following items is contained in a job description?",
A: "Duties to be performed",
B: "Marital status and age",
C: "Religious background",
D: "Salary to be paid",
answer: "A. Duties to be performed",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. The setting of sales target to be achieved within one year is",
A: "medium term planning.",
B: "operational planning.",
C: "strategic planning.",
D: "tactical planning.",
answer: "B. operational planning",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. The document that serves as proof of ownership which enables an importer to claim goods at the port is",
A: "a bill of lading.",
B: "a consular invoice.",
C: "a freight note.",
D: "an indent.",
answer: "A. a bill of lading.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. The issue that prevents small businesses from accessing loans for expansion is",
A: "lack of collateral.",
B: "inability to employ skilled labour.",
C: "inability to pay tax.",
D: "shorter life-span of the business.",
answer: "A. lack of collateral.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. One way of measuring the productivity of a firm is by using the",
A: "amount of capital invested.",
B: "efficiency of its labour force.",
C: "qualification of its labour force.",
D: "type of product.",
answer: "C. qualification of its labour force",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. Which of the following characteristics is advantageous for developing economies?",
A: "High export",
B: "High import",
C: "Low per capital income",
D: "Low standard of living",
answer: "A. High export",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question41",
question:  "41. Which of the following factors is a benefit to firms as a result of globalization?",
A: "Availability of cheap raw materials",
B: "Easy access to loans without collateral",
C: "Non payment of excise duties",
D: "No promotional charges",
answer: "A. Availability of cheap raw materials",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question42",
question:  "42. Which communication channel is used by a sales clerk when he gives monthly report on sales to his supervisor?",
A: "Diagonal communication",
B: "Downward communication",
C: "Horizontal communication",
D: "Upward communication",
answer: "D. Upward communication",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question43",
question:  "43. Absolute cost advantage in international trade is basically intended to",
A: "reduce specialization.",
B: "reduce dependency on import.",
C: "remove trade barriers.",
D: "increase world output.",
answer: "B. reduce dependency on import",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question44",
question:  "44. A firm that allows its branch managers to make decisions that suit their local conditions is practising",
A: "centralization.",
B: "decentralization.",
C: "delegation.",
D: "departmentation.",
answer: "C. delegation.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question45",
question:  "45. When AB Enterprise gives Christmas package to its employees for achieving a year’s target, this constitute",
A: "benefit.",
B: "bonus.",
C: "cash discount.",
D: "trade discount.",
answer: "B. bonus.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question46",
question:  "46. Which of the following decisions should be taken by the management of a company to solve the problem of declining sales during a particular period of the year?",
A: "Non-programmed decision",
B: "Programmed decision",
C: "Strategic decision",
D: "Tactical decision",
answer: "D. Tactical decision",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question47",
question:  "47. A printer is an example of",
A: "a storage device.",
B: "a processing device.",
C: "an input device.",
D: "an output device.",
answer: "D. an output device.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question48",
question:  "48. An organization that goes for a loan to pay the deposit for the cost of a vehicle with the balance to be paid by installment, acquires the vehicle by",
A: "debenture.",
B: "hire purchase agreement.",
C: "mortgage.",
D: "sale and lease back.",
answer: "B. hire purchase agreement",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question49",
question:  "49. Which of the following objectives influences individuals to start their own businesses?",
A: "Political positions",
B: "Profit motive",
C: "Production of inferior goods",
D: "Tax avoidance",
answer: "B. Profit motive",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question50",
question:  "50. The type of preference shares which are issued and can be purchased by a company at a later date are",
A: "participating preference shares.",
B: "irredeemable preference shares.",
C: "non-cumulative preference shares.",
D: "redeemable preference shares.",
answer: "C. non-cumulative preference shares.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},


]